### **BRANDON JAMES**

New York, NY 11434 ~ 718-916-8862~ <u>brandonj2858@gmail.com</u> <u>Github - Medium - Linkedin</u>

I am a full-stack web developer, all-around technology enthusiast and COMPTIA A+ certified technician with a passion for working with embedded systems. With experience in JavaScript, React, Redux, CSS, Flex-Box, Ruby, Rails and NodeJs. As a sports enthusiast, I understand the importance of teamwork, communication and being able to process and analyze data. I currently maintain a backend containing data for college football players entering the NFL draft. I am excited to show what I can bring to the table.

## TECHNICAL PROJECTS

### Top-Scouts - GitHub Backend | GitHub Frontend | Demo

An NFL draft scouting app for college players heading into the draft. With a ranking system and in-depth player reviews.

- Rails backend utilizing BCrypt and JavaScript Web Token for authentication.
- Used vanilla CSS to build out most of the app including the tables.
- Worked with dynamic forms for watchlist creation as well as commenting functionality.
- Used Redux and React hooks for state management.
- Used Redux to create actions, to reuse code in multiple components.

#### Tetris-Clone - GitHub - | Demo

A web-based clone of Tetris. Which includes level increases, drop time decreases based on level, row and score counters.

- Utilized built in react hooks to maintain state. Created custom hooks for callback functions and state.
- Created functions to calculate game score based on the level and rows cleared.
- Utilized styled components library and imported fonts to design each component.
- Created functions using React for collision detection on the x and y axis.

### Clonegram - GitHub | Demo

Instagram Clone where users can add pictures, follow other users, edit and update their profiles..

- PHP backend utilizing the Laravel framework. Authorization through PHP artisan commands.
- Used validations for login as well as post creation.
- Used serializers to gain access to data from a foreign key.
- Used Model events to automatically create a Profile for a newly registered user.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Frontend** - JavaScript, React, Redux, ES6, HTML, CSS, Flex-box, Tables **Backend** - Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Node.js, PostgreSQL, Github, PHP/Laravel

Other - Microsoft Office, Oracle VM Virtualbox, CMD Line, Terminal, Windows Server 2012

**Certifications** - CompTIA A+

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### Brandenz LLC, Hartford, CT

September 2016 — Present

# **Residential Real Estate Company**

- Maintained communication with tenants ensuring proper upkeep of the units.
- Maintained spreadsheets for two 6-family properties, with data pertaining to overall income and expenditures.
- Created reports for prospective properties for purchase.

#### Amazon Inc.

**September 2018 — May 2019** 

### RTS Helpdesk Assistant Level I/II

- Helped to plan and assign routes to over 300 couriers on a daily basis.
- Provided real-time updates and support via ad-hoc connection.
- Performed troubleshooting company ID Scanners, printers, laptops and other hardware.
- Utilized ticketing system to maintain organization when dealing with different issues and hardware.
- Set up VPN connections for employees as well as courier companies.

### CitiStorage, Brooklyn, NY

**January 2016 — August 2017** 

## **Archive Management Company**

Customer Service Rep

- Answered telephones and resolved customer issues in a timely and efficient manner.
- Processed and transmitted customer's web, fax and phone orders to the warehouse for shipping.
- Worked on projects and spreadsheets for various departments in the company.

# CitiStorage, Brooklyn, NY

(Summers) June 2012 —September 2014

### **Archive Management Company**

Record Center Clerk

- Maintained organization of different files based on identification numbers.
- Organized and barcoded boxes in the warehouse to ensure easy retrieval and preparation for shipment.

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor's Degree in Economics—In Progress (86 Credits Earned)

**August 2015- May 2017** 

City University of New York, Brooklyn College